[Music]
welcome welcome welcome to my kitchen
guys and today four of the ultimate raw
vegan bundle really stoked to be here
with you today it's a little different
really excited for this it's going to be
a lot of fun we're going to have a sushi
party with kristy and coke she made a
entire raw vegan sushi course for the
ultimate raw vegan bundle one of 36
books courses all raw vegan healthy
lifestyle mindset yoga
at an incredible discount like 98 off
for the ultimate raw vegan bundle you
can get the course and the whole bundle
and both of our books i have my 21 day
summer meal plan in the link in either
of our bios and
yeah it's only here till the 11th so you
know today we're going to have this
sushi feast party where we're both going
to make some sushi together i'm going to
make a version of how i kind of make it
and she's going to make her specialty a
new role that she actually hasn't shared
before and we're both going to kind of
contrast and share and give tips and
tricks sushi hey how's it going
christian
hi i'm fine
good to see you guys
for joining me today and this is gonna
be lots of fun i think this was such a
great suggestion you had to have a sushi
party together both of us make some
sushi
yes oh i love to make sushi i think you
already
understand that
yeah
absolutely absolutely hey you you
probably now can't see my my desk hey so
i might have to readjust here
yes i had the same problem so i'm going
to try to make it
so you see my table also
technical difficulties this is what
happens when it's your first time let's
see so standing up i might be a little
funny so i'm gonna bring my chair in
here oh wow this is so comfy now we're
just comfy and cozy
so i hear that you're making a new
i have to adjust also
yeah it's all right it's all right so i
hear you're making a new sushi for today
is this true
yes uh oh i was so excited i all my
creativity went into this sushi party oh
i'm so happy blessed by that that's
awesome
i think oh is
is my table visible yes it's visible at
the very least if you lift it up is it's
just on the bottom
okay
i'm ready
perfect perfect so how do you want to do
this i mean maybe we start with each
component and we each talk about how we
make it
well um
first i think first i want to
thank you chris because you are one of
my inspirations to
start with all these sushis this
they are in the video and of course and
in the bundle
um so um
yes for me this is a very big honor to
have you live with you and to share
my
creativity and my sushis with you so
because you are one of the
first times i really
thought well oh there's so much possible
with sushi
and um
and i asked you also to
write a comment in my book so i'm very
pleased about this
um
oh i have to excuse my english is not
very low so i'm dutch
oh good as much better than my dutch
i think so yes
definitely definitely no i'm 100 times
over honored and it is so awesome too
just that your your whole sushi book is
amazing you know like i love raw sushi i
played with it a little bit i know you
mentioned that my uh my better than nori
was a bit of an inspiration at one point
which is just for anyone who doesn't
know it's like a
uh terrestrial form of nori making it by
yourself rather than buying nori sheets
because in the past i didn't really use
nori sheets it's hard to get good
quality nori sheets we are lucky today
we can get certified raw vegan organic
and stuff but most of the stuff you get
in stores is pretty poor quality and
your book is just is phenomenal you know
it goes into way more depth
way more varieties of sushi and types of
rolling papers and stuff like that then
that i've done myself so i was really
tickled pink that it inspired you to
bring up even more creativity and more
things that we can all enjoy
and your course in the bundle is amazing
as well so that's awesome so people can
learn from the fine-tuned
application right because you read a
recipe book yeah it's good it's helpful
you know you learn a lot but you learn
so much more from that hands-on like
visual
audio kind of approach and bringing all
of those tips together
so
before we jump into that i do want to
quickly say
um
i'd love for you to share a little bit
of your story for those who haven't you
know haven't maybe heard you before
and uh just kind of what got you into
raw food and
this whole health journey and wanting to
make raw sushi
yeah
well my my raw vegan journey started 15
years ago oh no 17 years ago
when i went to a spiritual retreat and i
was challenged to eat only raw yeah and
um i had a history of of um
very many illnesses i um i'm covered
with eczema i
have asthma
allergies and a lot a lot a lot of food
allergies
and
i struggled this
many many many years and
with the raw vegan
lifestyle
on this spiritual retreat was only for
one week so it was not very
long
but it was like a epiphany because uh
all the foods that i uh i could eat
so i had no allergies uh because the
foods i was allergic to
uh weren't in the diet
so this for me was was like uh yeah like
a struck like a lightning bolt because
also because it was it felt me so
energetic and so uh
good and and
well it opened a whole new road in my
life
but i still
was very sick so it's um i think i
struggled another 10 years
with going on and off and uh finding my
way
and um every time i tried the raw vegan
lifestyle i became more sick so i
thought it must be
yeah this is not good
because i know
raw vegan is healthy and going to heal
me
but i'm i'm sick
every time i try this
so
and the answer to that question came uh
yeah
i think seven years ago and
it was a topical steward addiction
and this is that the topical steroids i
used on my body were the problem of
making me sick
because
these
prescribed drugs
had an effect on your total body and
and then i had to go into withdrawal and
topical steroid withdrawal is is a
is a really a way through hell
because your skin has to build it up
from completely nothing and
um i shared some photos online on my
journey uh to get off the topical
steroids and it was a moment it was
life-threatening so
um this is something you don't have to
do on your own you have to
i had a lot of help around me to go
through this withdrawal
and
one of the things that helped me was not
to go raw vegan but to go
plant-based low-fat
and slow the detox a little bit down
but i always know from the raw vegan is
my is my go-to
yeah so um
i'm a little bit emotional to tell my
story i'm sorry it's okay it's okay
it's it's really amazing and all the
things you've healed from and gone
through you know and is very well
documented on your instagram page shares
so much information
so
we don't have to go too too deep into
that but it is just a blessing that you
do share and that you're putting it all
out there for people to see because
it is so challenging when you don't know
you know like the correct route and you
know things that you feel are you know
going to help end up causing some more
pain and you know deep cleansing
reactions and i think it's really
amazing that you mentioned that you
needed to take a bit of a slower
approach and that even though you found
raw food to be incredibly healing and to
feel so good it was just a little bit
too aggressive for you in that period of
time you're coming off of the
medications yeah
and it's um the reason why it's
emotional also for me
is because for me it was a dream come
true i always wanted healing in my life
because i in a child i was bullied a lot
because of my skin
and
i thought it was possible but i didn't
think it was possible in this lifetime
so for me it's like a dream come true
and the message i want to share because
i'm not there yet i'm my healing is
still in process but um
i want to share that healing is possible
it's possible to have a skin
that is um
yeah that is that is soft and that is
not covered with wounds and that's um
this is making me emotional because
i really hope that people are hearing
this and and
and seeing this there's hope and there's
a possibility to get off of your
prescribed drugs and to
um to heal um
yeah as much as you possible uh
and this yeah
i i think this is making me emotional
not not my way i know i'm a strong woman
i i've proven that to myself and um
so um yeah i really want to share people
also with this bundle i find it's
it's not for me the bundle it's it's for
reaching out to people and and telling
them it's it's possible to heal even if
you have something
your your whole life
yeah that's so beautiful and it's so
important to say because you know that's
i think that's the beauty of the bundle
and just community right like we're all
coming together and sharing our
experiences and sharing the things we've
recovered from and healed from and there
are a lot of things that people think
are irreversible or told or irreversible
or you just got to live with you know
whether it's being sick multiple times
per year or you know just my last
interview with jumps too intense acne
or menstrual cramps or we're talking
about even things like you know
depression or joint aches and pains or
diabetes
you know the body is meant to be in a
nice like natural state of health and
really oftentimes it just takes
providing those conditions you know and
getting out of the way of ourselves and
some of societal society's beliefs kind
of growing through and
past those right yeah
i was with my doctor a
dermatologist a
few months ago and he said no you have a
genetic condition you have a skin
problem i say look at me
do i have a skin problem i don't see it
so um and they are looking like with a
little um
how do you call it um
who's search for for the for the little
uh yeah
things on my skin that
suppose it doesn't supposed to be there
but it felt so humiliating to see
because i am uh i feel my skin and my
skin is so much better
and
and the doctors they want to yeah stay
in their
point of view
so it was yeah
i didn't like it but
i think
i've proven it to myself and this is the
most
important thing
i think i think that's why it's so
important and that's why we're all doing
this bundle together is because we've
seen the healing right and you know we
can't blame the doctors necessarily
they're operating from what they see
most often and the general mainstream
results they get and they think this
isn't reversible because i haven't seen
it reversed right and we are seeing it
reversed and we're
shining a light on the reality
of you know like natural healing and
health and the power of the body and
it's i mean science is catching up
science knows more and more that it's
not your genetics uh your genetics are
expressed dependent upon your diet and
just by changing your diet having
incredible healthy foods in your
lifestyle and deep breaths and a
holistic kind of attitude your gene
expressions turn on or off right so
they don't have to run our lives it's
it's a beautiful thing and the more of
us doing this whether it's just us we're
making and creating the books or
everyone who's taking part in this and
who's you know taking this lifestyle on
and gathering all the information and
the recipes and going through the
courses and applying to their life
that's well that's what's going to
spread it out right that's what's going
to change doctors minds and it's
beautiful because we have you know we
have doctors on something we've got the
raw vegan doctor and she's out there
changing people's minds and there's more
and more people just like her that are
from different backgrounds that are
classically taught that nope that's not
possible food doesn't make a difference
you know and their minds are being
opened because of actual experience and
the science that is growing from that as
well
yeah
and yeah about the raw vegan sushi book
i started to
make sushi
because uh i have learned in my healing
process that creativity is a lot of part
of healing so
um
i'm blessed with creativity i think
everyone is creative
creative but
um
i'm also an artist that make a lot of
paintings and
other things
but uh for me the the um
to to
be creative with your food and creating
beautiful things is an act of self-love
and
it helped me to
in the in the process of being very sick
uh helped me to
yeah in my mind create a lot of
recipes trying things it was the one
thing i stood up
for in
out of my bed in the period and it was
very bad with me so um
i stood up i made my dinner my make my
food
my breakfast lunch and dinner and then
between i was in my bed but it was the
one thing um keep me going so for me
this this sushi book is also
um yeah
and a way to um
to let the world show uh that creativity
is is a part of of healing
absolutely absolutely no i feel that 110
and i do again just encourage everyone
to uh to go follow christiane on her
page you can click through here when
we're over with this and then grab the
bundle through her give her some love
and support uh you'll get the sushi book
my book and 34 others courses meal plans
a whole bunch of good stuff and then of
course your entire sushi book is on your
website as well just quickly what is
that
what oh your sushi book my name is my
website so there we go perfect perfect
so we might as well jump into the sushi
because i bet you a bunch of people are
excited for that yeah and this is this
is the first time i've done like a dual
demo so this is kind of this is really
lots of fun um
have you ever done something like this
before like a dual demo at the same time
no i i have to admit this is my third
life or something so oh well honored by
that that's a lot of fun um do you want
to start by
going over ingredients or do you want to
dive into
one of the parts of one component of the
sushi
well i uh i have set my book uh with a
lot of chapters uh of the the parts of
the sushi so
maybe we can start with what do you
do you use as a rice replacement
perfect
i know you have a bunch of different
options so i'm really excited to see
what uh what you've chosen today
well i um i
prefer also a combination
so
i had a cauliflower yeah and some celery
egg
oh nice yeah
and
i use
the wet chopped methods uh
[Music]
for the uh for the cauliflower i it is
from lisa and it's i really like it
because it's very quick and you get a
very fine
yeah grain like uh substance
awesome awesome
and uh the celeriac i uh grades
okay uh what size of grater do you use
for that a very very uh small grater
okay and i only have this in in my uh
as a manual thing
yeah um
because if i do use a food processor
it's it's it doesn't have
uh a
structure i like because
um for the inside out susie we're making
inside out susie so yes
i'm very excited about that
um
you have to i use the fine uh grated
celeriac
to
go into the
wrap around the cauliflower rice so it's
it becomes more
cohesive i thought yeah
yeah it makes sense i think it almost
become like a lattice where like it
would uh seal it in together that's
really smart
yes
so i like um all the another option is a
sweet potato white sweet potato
or
a turnip
or a
kohlrabi
so these are all very firm
and if you grade it they become like
yeah a small
capsule for the for the sushi
for the cauliflower
oh very cool i'm really excited to see
how you uh encapsulate it and the
technique that you use yeah
so i already prepped it oh good that's
awesome
so yeah i don't know if it's very
possible but this is the the
the cauliflower it's very fine yeah the
celery egg yeah and here i put it
together
and to have another adhesive is i put a
date in it so the dual date is very soft
so i dropped it into the rice
and this is my rice replacement today
so what what ratio of cauliflower to
celery did you use
one-on-one
one-on-one yes okay just just so people
don't know too the the wet chop so you
fill the blender with water or or rather
you fill the the blender with as much
cauliflower as you're using
and then you fill water over top water
first water first okay yes so uh and
then i put some like two-thirds and then
i put uh the cauliflower in and because
when i put the cauliflower first it's
it's not going around in the blender
okay
so
i put it on later and then the water is
all around and it can uh
well in 10 seconds no not five seconds
it's
yeah on medium speeds it's it's ready
and then you said you just pour it out
through a sieve and squeeze some of the
water out and you've got perfect rice
um not
a nut milk bag i use it
yeah yeah awesome awesome well i haven't
made my rice yet but it won't take me
too long so i'll explain mine and do it
very quickly
um
so i'm making a very simple simple rice
as well i want to try that trick with
the celerate because that sounds really
good and that's one of the hardest
things with inside out rolls is things
falling apart
so the the technique i've used is one i
really like ginger and sometimes i like
to make my sushi so that i don't need to
put any sauces or anything on it it's
just ready as is so i have like 50 grams
of ginger here and
i didn't peel everything off the outside
if i was a little bit less lazy and a
little more prepared i probably would
have
but i'm just going to take that ginger
and
the wood worked really good in the wet
chop and in truth i think the wet chop
is easier for clean up and a little bit
more efficient
i just didn't i ended up using my food
processor and it's kind of good to show
the different techniques right but so
i'm just going to put that in the food
processor
and
because i want to make sure that the
ginger is pretty fine i'm going to
actually pulse that up first
so
i'll see if i can do this properly
without
anything so i'm just going to pulse that
stupid i'd have some elevator music i
could play while this is happening
all right so that's pretty well chopped
up i'm gonna get some off the outside
edges
and
then i just have cauliflower i'm only
going to make two rolls so i have like i
think 230 grams or so of cauliflower-ish
something like that i'm just gonna put
that in there
um
sometimes i like to add like a
like onion powder or something like that
to add a little extra flavor to the rice
but today i have just
a little bit
simpler
but i find about this much about half a
cauliflower is about as much as i can
fit in a food processor so that's one of
the good things about the wet chop is
you can actually do a lot more at once i
think than you can easily in a food
processor
so
just gonna do that real quick
and then
pulse that up
hopefully
easily
it's funny i'm never behind the food
processor when i'm using it sitting down
like this it's a
little more awkward
oh there we go that should go down
all right so let's pulse that up
[Music]
there we go
so i got that in there
oftentimes i transfer that to a big bowl
and mix it in there
but i think
because i didn't grab a big bowl and
just to
make this a little bit easier in one pot
what i'm going to do is
add
some lemon juice to it
and
add maybe about a t tablespoon of lemon
juice to it just to kind of wet the rice
a little bit up watch out for seeds
oh gosh
how embarrassing
what happens yeah
seeds happen right they sometimes just
happen
part of uh
of uh eating food
absolutely yeah absolutely
that's uh
the plants
reproduction so
yeah all right i think plants wants us
to eat the seeds so they can
produce reproduce themselves
yeah exactly we uh i i i often said one
day i'd like to have a planting party
where everyone is just encouraged for a
few
days before the planting party to eat
all of their favorite fruits and make
sure they swallow the seeds without
chewing them and then we'll just have a
big pooping party all over the place you
know and have that natural fertilizer
just have a
and everyone has their own little tree
you know remember what spot you're at
and like who knows it's the luck of the
draw which is going to grow right
maybe one day
so my little oh i got to lick my fingers
i apologize
um
my little trick here
for trying to make the rice stickier
is to mix in some
chia seeds
so i have a tablespoon of chia seeds for
about a half a pound of cauliflower
and i'm using a magic bullet blender oh
gosh i don't want to have that come off
in there
i was about to blend up the seal that's
that's not no bueno
so
we got that here and it's luckily a
quick thing if you don't have a magic
bullet then a regular blender or a seed
grinder works
oh no
wow is amazing
somehow
it decided to
blend up the seal which is really a
shame oh
that has never happened before but
that's what happened today so we'll try
and get that out so that we're not
eating uh rubber
unfortunately i think i'm gonna have to
pour this out and then pour it back in
and hopefully
i'll be able to
actually still blend this without that
seal that's really a shame ah
that's a big surprise we use this a lot
and that's never
happened okay let's see
it's amazing how much a tablespoon is
like
it seems like so little for some things
and do you always um
ground your chia seeds
yes yeah i always i always grind it and
i've always used well i've used the
vitamix sometimes too
but
grind it just so that it
creates more surface area
in order
to coat the rice even more and create
kind of like a slightly sticky texture
of the rice
yeah
so let's hope that this still works well
without that seal i'm guessing it should
there we go
there we go and now we really just have
chia powder basically yeah
and i'll quickly just uh
pour that loosely over this
rice
and
oh it's a lot it's more than you think
it really puffs up when you make the
that
and again normally actually i just put
this in a bowl and stir it with a spoon
maybe i'm living on the edge here but
i'm just going to pulse it in here just
to kind of incorporate it
all right so
i got my
rice done so while i get this rice out
of here into my bowl maybe you can go
into the next steps on yours
yes
well i have my filling
my feeling that today is
asparagus oh
nice i
have them frozen
i i boil them
once a year
and i freeze them
and these are frozen and taut
nice some cucumber
and some marinated portobello
so
i have marinated it now in some orange
juice and
some
um yeah it's called pickled wheat i
think it's a it's a
sea headphone
that lives near the sea not in the sea
yeah and it's very salty and
it's very nice to have some extra flavor
and some black pepper so this is a very
easy marination marinade
i don't know what the word is um and
i have less like slices
from it
okay perfect so where did you get the is
it
did you say it was a sea asparagus or
what was this the the really salty one
yeah
um i think it's called pickled weeds
yeah silicon uh the the leather name is
silicon
okay
um it's it's yeah it's like uh
i i don't really know the dutch word
so see
so it's it's uh it's a little uh
vegetables that is very salty and very
tasty
nice
that's awesome right and that's this uh
okay can you use as a salt replacement
that's awesome i wonder we'll see so i
just recently was turned on to this
stuff called
yeah i bet you this is it called green
salt
and it's dehydrated salicornia is that
the same stuff yes it is yeah so i was
just recently turned on to this by chef
aj she had the creator of this on her
show
and they had a discount code and i was
like oh give this a try because it is
like you said it's just it's a plant
that's naturally really high in organic
sodium because it's bound by carbon and
they take really good care of it they uh
they use salt water on it to make sure
that it's you know really high quality
and lots of sodium in it and it's dry so
it's salt free but high in natural
sodium
and you know what because you mentioned
that i'm going to actually just add a
sprinkle to my rice i think too i wasn't
planning on that and this isn't yeah i
actually do have a discount code for
this
but uh no wait no i'm totally lying i
don't have discount code for this i
wanted to get one but they never gave me
one yet but uh
kind of interesting
yes i love the sea vegetables
you can't get it fresh it's it's so
tasty yeah you know i remember um like
sea vegetables that
for example have had um
what's it called lance quarters growing
by the sea that's just like so salty and
so delicious
um it is pretty high oxalate so you
don't want to eat it like non-stop huge
salads but it is very powerful very good
and even sea purslane like when i was in
maui i was uh and also in some places in
uh in indonesia i was finding like
amazing sea purslane along the sea and
they're big kind of succulent kind of
bulbs that
just one it almost tastes like a black
olive like they're so amazing
yeah
it's perfect well
i live in the netherlands so sea
vegetables are are our thing uh you know
yeah i i like sea vegetables for sure
and it's funny because i like you know
at some points in my raw food journey i
completely like avoided them you know i
was like oh i shouldn't have sea
vegetables um you know we're terrestrial
but
you know since then i've learned more
and i've tried things out for myself and
just seeing how things feel in my body
and you know done research and
there are so many trace minerals and
different components of seaweeds that as
long as you're getting good quality i
think that's one of the most important
things like you know we were talking
about seaweeds because of their natural
um you know uh
binding properties they buy heavy metals
and even radiation you don't want to be
getting like fukushima seaweed for
example um
and i think more and more we're going to
have closed environment grown seaweeds
and i know there's a closed environment
growing algaes and stuff like that that
really monitor but uh
it makes a big difference i think and it
can be a really great part of a balanced
raw food diet
so and that's the last thing i'm going
to put into my
sushi is is
like
a sauce but very thick
with
hands or hemp seeds
um tomato sun-dried tomato and some
dates
so you have like a little um
sauce between the
the filling
perfect
yeah so i'm going to do that i think
putting price on my
noise feeds i have like a two-third of
the noise sheets
yeah
and i use a silicon
rolling mat
it doesn't stick on it so this is uh
if you have a bamboo mat it's uh the
rice will stick on it but if you have a
silicon one
well it's very easy is that one um
is it actually like a full sheet of
silicon or is it
yeah yes
yeah
that's awesome yeah that's awesome i
gotta get one of those because i have a
bamboo one and then i have this plastic
one which i put uh just a plastic bag
around which works okay but yeah
that looks way better i haven't seen
that before
yeah it was in some cooking uh shop
i like to go there and see all the new
gadgets
yeah absolutely yeah that's awesome
and i'm putting my rice on it and um
really press it down so it's it's go all
into
each other
can you push your camera just a little
bit down uh point just a little bit more
down
i'm going to try it
okay
well i'll let everyone know here
this is the this is the sushi that i
have it's a certified raw and organic
nori and they do testing to make sure
there isn't like crazy you know heavy
metals or anything in it you know on a
regular basis it's again certified raw
organic kosher tested in the usa
chemical radiation free i do actually
have a discount code for this one so
when i found this i was really stoked by
it i wrote them and they ended up giving
me a five percent off discount code
which is just a
c h r i k
five so qrik five um which i'll put in
the show notes uh after the fact but
it's pretty sweet stuff pretty darn good
deal it's just raw nori.com for that
stuff so
i'm gonna do the same thing um i think
that it's a good plan like you have for
the uh the two-thirds or the
smaller amount of roll i always end up
with a little bit extra
yeah um
but my sheets are full and i'm pretty
lazy so i'm just going to use a full
sheet myself and do the same i'm going
to pack down
uh half of the rice that i have because
that for me this is about half of uh
half a cauliflower and makes about
two decent rolls is what i figure
so i'll do the same things pack
half my stuff on the sushi paper
well i put it on my sushi
and it's a thin layer
and
press it really down this with this
spatula
this is my favorite spatula i use it for
everything
ah
that's awesome i have um it's awesome
you know like the little different
things you know you're using a spatula i
use a little pie scooper yeah yeah
and i'm flipping it around so the rice
is coming on the sushi
mat
awesome
and the sushi is becoming of the nori is
becoming a little bit wet
but that is not a problem
for me it's not a problem
so do you do you press your rice onto
the entire surface of your entire uh
yes as much as possible to the edges
awesome
yeah i do i do somewhat similar although
i think with um because i'm using a full
sheet i i push it almost to the edge but
not quite on the top like it's it's the
edge on most parts but not quite to the
top on the on the top
now i'm using the
the portabello as first
the
asparagus
what are you putting into your
sushi
well
i'm going to
put some uh
alpha alpha sprouts oh yes
um some slivered sun-dried tomatoes so i
have these really nice soft sun-dried
tomatoes i'm just gonna
cut those into slippers
i got some green onion
some red pepper
and avocado
can you show the red pepper again yeah
absolutely
oh yes this is this is like a bell
pepper or not
yep yeah just a sweet bell pepper so i
um i just took like a quarter of a bell
pepper and i i meant to have some
cucumber but i
actually forgot to purchase it so
well it happens
yeah i almost decided to put celery in
it but i was like you know what that's
that's not quite what i want today
but i always say that making mistakes or
leaving things out it's it's uh it's
always a
a way to stimulate your creativity you
have to look for different
alternatives and
yeah
so making mistakes in sushi is not
possible
exactly yeah at the very worst you
decide hey i'm not going to do that next
time
so i'm going to try and do the same and
flip mine that's always the challenging
one but i'm just going to actually slide
my paper off onto the
cutting board i have underneath
and then put my
sushi rolling mat on top of it
yeah and sandwich it and flip it
and then there we go i safely have
my sushi on there
now let's see what do i want to put
first
what do you said you put your mushrooms
on first hey
i put my mushrooms on first yes they
take the most space of it
so this is what it looks like
it's filled
that's awesome what did you marinate
your mushrooms with um
a little bit of orange juice
the pickled wheat the green salt you
said and
some black pepper
nice that's awesome that's
awesome all right i put down my sprouts
first and i'm gonna put half of the red
pepper
half of the
sun-dried tomatoes and half of the i'm
gonna go i'm gonna go all in i'm gonna
put half of the
avocado in there which is quite a lot of
avocado but
should be really delicious
yeah it's also the ratio of how much
filling and uh how much space you have
in the inside out roll so
this is uh this is the challenge for me
in uh but alfalfa is is very good
because it fills a lot of uh
uh of the space
yes it's nice and fluffy too so you can
like you know it kind of compresses
everything and keeps stuff intact inside
there
your sun-dried tomatoes are pretty darn
tasty
sometimes i like to make like a
sorry
this is the the exciting moment so
trying oh you're gonna roll
yes i'm going to roll let's get rolling
i gotta still put my green onion in mine
how's the roll one going
it's going great
yes that's good
oh gosh i'm a little bit nervous
it's a little bit moist i think for me
yeah
so um
yeah i have to strain my cauliflower
more the next time
okay
but
well
it's an inside out roll
i think mine is gonna be a little dry
for my for my uh for today i created a
new sushi yeah and what i did is i'm
going to make it into a hole
and
with some
some daikon oh
nice
so how are you going to prepare the dark
one
yesterday i marinated my daikon i
marinated in um
barley juice powder so it becomes a
little bit green
yeah
and i marinated it in
beet powder
so it becomes very red
and kokuma
so it becomes orange
so i have a like
all these little
um slices
um
going on top of my sushi oh on top
that's awesome yes it looks like is it
near gary or what is it with the stuff
on top
it's it's daikon
it's taiko radish
beautiful i sliced it very thin
this is going on top and making a lot of
color to it
nice
nice i'm gonna i'm gonna attempt to roll
mine and before i do i'm gonna drip a
teeny bit of lemon juice on the top side
of my paper to hopefully
make it stick a little bit more when i
roll it
just kind of rub the lemon on there a
little bit
oh gosh
this is this is the moment of truth
yeah
that doesn't work
it can all go
completely south you never know
oh lord
oh jesus i forgot something
what did you forgot
i realized the way i put the rice on
here is going to
have a big like
fold of sushi paper
so before i do that i'm going to
actually whoop i'm going to roll that
back and hope that didn't just roll ruin
it up i can actually fold my sushi paper
over
and squeeze a little bit of lemon juice
on it that's that's why you know having
a smaller size sushi paper like you do
makes a lot of sense
yeah
it's been a little while since i made
this i made a recipe video of it and i
haven't made it since because it is
challenging
um
but there we go so i'm going to fold
that over
and let's hope and pray that this works
perfectly now
putting a bit of pressure
yeah so far so good
oh gosh
i am afraid
keep on rolling keep on rolling keep on
rolling
not bad but i'm gonna keep and rolling
keep them rolling
squish that on there
i think it i think it's a i think it's
going to be passable
but i think i'm going to have to
roll it in
some saran wrap before i cut it
yeah
well i'm going to show that also so uh
what i'd um
because what i would use this is like a
cling foil
yeah
and then um
it's um with this with the
little little diakon
and i put it on top
and i use the cling foil for cutting for
cutting
oh just just yeah putting that dicot on
top i guess that also kind of like
encapsulates it a little bit as well so
it makes it into like a nice little
cover that will help it stay together
even better hey
yeah
that's awesome that's a good tip
i don't uh roll it around but i don't
only under
the sides so
um
you don't
roll it all into the sushi
let's see
if it's possible to see that i have
put the cling file
on it
and the little scales yeah
yeah
and for me then it's possible to cut so
i cut through the
cling foil
yeah yeah without then it ends up being
more likely to fall apart hey
yeah
i'm rolling mine on to my clink foil
carefully
and i'm gonna try my darn just to try
and roll it up so that it really pulls
it all together
there we go
oh lord
and how it's going
it's going pretty darn good it's um it
could have been just a little bit
tighter
but it's pretty good and i'm spinning up
the sides to try and
get the
the cling to really suck up and
make it so the sushi's as tight as i can
make it
there we go
there we go so i got it i got a sushi
log here that's looking pretty decent
oh yeah
it looks great
it's hard to see because my screen is so
little
i'll get i'll get nice and close so you
have a
little
a little saran oh
little sushi i got a little bit you can
see some of the paper over there
but
but i salvaged it pretty decently
i'll see this is mine
and i'm not
putting the cling foil all around it so
i'm going only
on top
oh so you just have it on top for yours
yes
you don't lie because then i can cut
through it and then i only remove the
foil and then the sushi is ready
nice
should we try and cut them yes
so i guess this do you find a wet knife
helps or do you find a certain kind of
knife is the best for you or what do you
usually use
well i have noticed that my new
ceramic knife is very sharp and it's
it's very good for this
but else i use a wet knife
so wet knife is always with sushi goods
better than
a unsharp knife
yeah absolutely absolutely i'm gonna rub
some lemon on my knife and
i'm gonna i'm gonna try um you know it's
funny
sometimes when i make raw sushi i just
leave it as a snake you know i just like
especially if it's not an inside out
roll i just you know just have it like a
burrito like a sushi burrito yeah
but this
i think i'm going to try and cut into i
can't decide if i cut it into four or s
or sorry into a six or eight but
how many slices do you like to cut yours
into
uh seven because i like the
i like the number
nice nice that's cool so when you cut it
into seven what do you where do you
start because i usually do it in either
um
uh six or eight because then i just cut
in the center and then i cut in the
center but where how do you start
i start at the end yes
and i
mostly the ends are this time this is
eight
[Music]
most uh the
um
mostly the ends are like a bit of a bit
fluffy and then
you can put it in another
bowl
and not present it but
yeah so
mostly it's 8
8 7 seven eight and the ants uh
go mostly into my mouth
yeah
that's the best place to put him i heard
[Laughter]
oh this is this is always the scary part
see like
i have my cut into four
and this like i could just leave it like
this and they'll stay beautiful
i know when i start to try and cut these
four into two more pieces each there's
the chance they'll start to fall out if
i'm not careful yeah
this is where a sharp knife really comes
in this is really important
are yours are all done
yeah
oh
i'm going to start i'm going to cut
just two at a time
but
i didn't do the cutting very good so
it's falling apart a little bit
that's the nature of this recipe this is
one of the harder ones i think
to keep together
yeah
oh
i i managed somehow to get part of my uh
part of my green onion on the outside of
the sushi roll that's interesting how
that happened oh and it wants to fall
apart because of that
so i'm going to put that one that way
there we go
let's see
but it looks very nice and i don't know
if you can see
oh
that looks awesome yeah
it's red on the other outside and the
portobello is a nice white and the green
from the asparagus
yeah i'm very pleased with it
we're gonna have to um
try and hold ours up really close to the
camera both at the same time and get a
nice screenshot
so that
i can use that for the video thumbnail
yeah
oh there we go
yeah i'm pretty pleased here as well
i kind of wish i would have
played it on some
something other than this cutting board
but we'll see
oh my
there we go just slipping that off
and
have you already tasted some
um
well
it sounds like it is not nice to talk
with your mouth also
but
if you see i i'm licking my fingers and
it's very good
i'm happy to hear
that's awesome
let's see oh
trying to find the edge
of the saran because you definitely want
to remove the saran before you eat
there we go
oh
i got one slice left here and then i'm
i'm caught up to you if i can find the
edge of the sushi or the there we go
oh
[Music]
let's see if i can flip this
no i don't want to flip it all right
so
i'm going to quickly blow some of the
stuff off
make the plate look a little nicer
all
all right get it in there oh gosh yes
oh
looks awesome
oh these are looking nice also oh should
we should we should we have some yours
look beautiful i love the uh the
covering on top that looks really really
awesome
[Music]
yeah
um
well shall we eat it
yeah let's give it a go um watermelon
lime is asking is that the technique
that sushi chefs use too you know i have
a friend who has a sushi restaurant in
canada called sushiro
and
i know that for the inside out rolls
that i've seen them use the uh the the
plastic wrap around the outside
technique even with rice
so that is a good technique all right
enjoy
thank you too
yes
even this is morning i still like it
it's awesome
it looks awesome
well that was a lot of fun
thank you so much for joining me and
everyone here today and sharing your
sushi technique and i really invite
everyone
to check out the bundle and christiane's
link or my own
and to check all of it out because you
know your sushi course is amazing it
goes way more in depth into various
different ways of making different sushi
different rices
different dipping sauces
so much fun delicious stuff great i mean
i have
read the book of ronnie of the the
with the myth he debunked and it was so
mind-blowing i really liked it and
and there are so many beautiful books in
the bundle
yeah absolutely
absolutely susannah is also about low
fats and
yes he's like
the scientist
explaining everything it's really nice
yes very well referenced right it's like
and i think that's just so important to
note that the the bundle itself is not
just recipes of course there's tons of
recipes and you know like courses such
as your own and meal plan such as mine
but there's a lot of really really
important information in there that can
make the hugest difference in in your
health because you know there are a lot
of different ways of doing a raw food
diet and the way that we're all coming
together is unified message from what
we've seen work the best for the largest
number of people and just really
streamline your health outcomes and
yes science-backed and well-referenced
you know amazing books and
things that can basically help you avoid
a lot of the pitfalls that some people
may find if they don't really have the
right information
yeah and help you heal because this is
still my message the healing is possible
even if you are sick 45 years out of the
50 you live
it's it's possible
yeah
awesome well thanks so much christianne
and give everyone give her a follow
thanks everyone for uh for spending your
time with us today if you're watching
the replay i hope you really enjoy it as
well and it encourages and inspires you
to make more raw vegan sushi and to lead
a healthier happier life with a balanced
raw food lifestyle so
i'm gonna have one more too
cheers
see you again christian
bye bye thank you so much
thank you it was so much fun
check out the ultimate ragian bundle
it's only here until april 11th
don't forget to check out my raw recipes
playlist in the top left the video just
for you in the top right subscribe for
more videos in the bottom right and get
your three free ebooks in the bottom
left
grab your free raw recipe app available
on iphone and android with over 100 free
raw recipes common fruit and vegetable
calorie breakdown freaking ross and food
combining shopping cart function and so
much more